Indira Murugan

indiramurugan8@gmail.com

(636)-346-5829) www.linkedin.com/in/indira-murugan 74349b152

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATION

Versatile, motivated Programmer/Developer with specializing in web and backend development. Proven supportive and enthusiastic team member with the ability to formulate problems, think creatively about solutions, and express a solution clearly and accurately. Experienced in assessing and prioritizing the urgency of requests to maximize efficiency and completion. Excellent at time management skills Including timely submission of required reports and documentation. Demonstrated ability to learn complex skills and concepts quickly and effectively.

Key Skills

- Python and C#
- Flask and ASP.Net
- MySQL, SQLAlchemy, Entity
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Visual Studio, MVC, GitHub, Git Bash
- ORACLE PL/SQL
- COBOL
- BASIC, FOX, DBASE
- MS Dos. UNIX

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

LiftOff LaunchCode, STL-2018

 Focusing on completion of project through agile planning and communications practices involving Sprint Planning, Daily Stand-up, Iteration review, Retrospective, organized around 2 week sprints. Project done: KashiHomeFood

Completed LC101 - LaunchCode course July 2017 - Dec 2017

- Gained knowledge in Universal Web concepts: HTML tags and forms, CSS selectors and style rules, Model-View-Controller design for web applications, retrieved and updated data using databases / SQL, Python as back-end language, Version control using Github.
- Proficient in programming: Core C#, C# collections, Data types, Static modifiers, objects and classes, class Inheritance, Polymorphism and Interfaces.
- Adept in creating and configuring controllers, persistent model classes via ADO.NET, created views using Razor templates.
- Acquired Skills in Python programming language: Data types and type casting, Mathematical and comparison operators, Data structures (Lists and Dictionaries), Created Functions, object and classes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Target Corporation, Chesterfield, MO OCT 2016 – MAY 2017

• As a Cashier

Lakhotia Computer Centre Coimbatore India JAN 1998 – MAY 1998

• As a faculty

Vigyan Bhavan, New Delhi, India MARCH 1996 – AUGUST 1997

• Managed IT projects as "Project Coordinator" and has hands on experience in setting up IT infrastructure.

Volunteered at LaunchCode, St. Louis, Missouri July 2018 - August 2018

• Helped new LaunchCode students in the class assignments

EDUCATION

LaunchCode, St. Louis, MO Dec 2017

• LC101

Masters in Computer application Jan 2000

• IGNOU, New Delhi, India

UPTRON ACL, Faridabad, India July 1994

• Diploma in Computer Application

University of Kurushetra, Haryana , India June 1993

• Bachelors of Commerce